<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Marketing Communications and Advertising"
    id="id-91ea4ac32d0f498495cbf2c31db37e38"
    documentation="Marketing Communications deals with overall communication to customers and markets. It develops and manages communications to the market, prospective and existing customers. Communications involves both the message and the media. It develops a message and manages its delivery through a bill insert, phone communication with customers, a web advertisement, social media, or any other appropriate mechanism. It also develops and manages interfaces with press/news, for example schedules press interviews, and manages an editorial calendar to plan placements, and so forth.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;It supports general marketing communications as well as those related to specific product offerings and marketing campaigns. As such it interacts with the Marketing Campaign Management and Product Promotion Development processes. &#xD;&#xA;A significant portion of marketing communication is advertising which draws the market’s attention to an enterprise typically for the purpose of inducing individuals and/or organizations to acquire an enterprise’s product offerings. This is accomplished by using of various forms of media, such as print, web, and broadcasts. An advertisement may appear on partner sites or other forms of media a partner uses.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;It includes determining the audience for the advertisement, establishing a budget for the advertisement, planning which media to use, entering into agreements with one or more partners with whom the advertisement will be co-developed/sponsored and jointly used, and choosing a message to be conveyed by the advertisement.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;In addition drawing attention to a product offering, an advertisement may also be used to enhance the image of the enterprise or announce one or more new offerings.">
  <properties
      key="Group"
      value="Operations"/>
  <properties
      key="BusinessFlow"
      value="Fulfillment"/>
  <properties
      key="BusinessFlow"
      value="Operations Readiness &amp; Support"/>
  <properties
      key="BusinessFlow"
      value="Fulfillment"/>
  <properties
      key="Domain"
      value="Market Sales"/>
  <properties
      key="Group"
      value="Strategy to Readiness"/>
</archimate:Capability>
